Hi name is Scott and I'm the owner of Climb On indoor rock climbing gym in Wilmington, North Carolina.
Today we are going to discuss rock climbing techniques.
Technique is very important in rock climbing to keep you on the wall and climbing efficiently.
These are things that you can learn at your local indoor rock climbing gym.
Some of the things that you might learn to begin with would be to keep your arms straight while you climb, and not bent.
The more you keep your arms in to your body, the more fatigued your muscles are going to become.
So when we are climbing we try to keep our arms as straight as we can while we climb.
The other technique that you might learn is footwork.
Footwork is extremely important in rock climbing.
You don't want to have to do a hole bunch of pull ups, you really want to use your feet to balance.
So what I'm going to do is push up with my legs and try to keep my arms straight.
Sometimes there is nothing to stand on so you might have to do what's called a smear, which is actually just using the wall for your feet to walk up.
Other techniques might be stemming out to use another wall for balance for your leg.
These techniques are all things that can be learned at your local indoor rock climbing gym by a qualified professional.
Rock climbing is dangerous so we do ask that you go get instruction.
This has been rock climbing technique.